<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on</title><link>/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/historical-cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/historical-cases/</guid><description>McKeever Case McMillan Case FBI Procedures - what were the procedures that followed from the McKeever case? Watergate Tapes What did the tapes contain and why where they important? What was the problem with the recordings? What was this &amp;lsquo;problem&amp;rsquo; an example of in forensic audio? Reevaluation of the Assassination of President Kennedy What was the source of the recording? What was the finding from the analysis by BBN and Mark R.</description></item><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/lab-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/lab-instructions/</guid><description>Remove consistent noise Make sure the amplitude statistics window is visible. Select all of your audio and then click the scan button. Now you can see the amplitude statistics for the audio. This will tell you how much headroom there is for normalization. Clicking on the icon next to each dB reading will jump you to that position in the audio. Next, normalize the audio recording to -3 dB. This is important so that the noise is more audible.</description></item><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/twenty-thousand-hertz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/twenty-thousand-hertz/</guid><description>Malaysian Airlines Issues Edited tape Part sounds like it was re-recorded through a speaker Also:
Authentication What problems does Kent say there are with authentication because of modern technology?
Trayvon Martin Case Shouting in the 911 call, debate over whether it was Martin or Zimmerman. What would the difference have made?
Mel Gibson He was harassing his girlfriend. Kent needed to prove that it was his voice, and that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t edited.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 Project 2 Project 3</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/24, 8/26 Tuesday 8/24:
Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? Any idea what forensic audio is? Syllabus Perusall signup I will assign readings, videos, or podcasts through Perusall.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 492 – Sound Forensics
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021
Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021
Course Meeting Time and Location: Tuesday / Thursday 1:00 pm – 2:15 pm TCB 209
Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item></channel></rss>