<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on</title><link>/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/historical-cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/historical-cases/</guid><description>McKeever Case McMillan Case FBI Procedures - what were the procedures that followed from the McKeever case? Watergate Tapes What did the tapes contain and why where they important? What was the problem with the recordings? What was this &amp;lsquo;problem&amp;rsquo; an example of in forensic audio? Reevaluation of the Assassination of President Kennedy What was the source of the recording? What was the finding from the analysis by BBN and Mark R.</description></item><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/lab-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/lab-instructions/</guid><description>Remove consistent noise Make sure the amplitude statistics window is visible. Select all of your audio and then click the scan button. Now you can see the amplitude statistics for the audio. This will tell you how much headroom there is for normalization. Clicking on the icon next to each dB reading will jump you to that position in the audio. Next, normalize the audio recording to -3 dB. This is important so that the noise is more audible.</description></item><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-3/twenty-thousand-hertz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-3/twenty-thousand-hertz/</guid><description>Malaysian Airlines Issues Edited tape Part sounds like it was re-recorded through a speaker Also:
Authentication What problems does Kent say there are with authentication because of modern technology?
Trayvon Martin Case Shouting in the 911 call, debate over whether it was Martin or Zimmerman. What would the difference have made?
Mel Gibson He was harassing his girlfriend. Kent needed to prove that it was his voice, and that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t edited.</description></item><item><title>Consonants Lab</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-12/consonants-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-12/consonants-lab/</guid><description>Now lets see some of these properties of consonants in Praat.
Record these stopped consonant words Pit, abbey, tin, cool, butter. Find the rapid onset for each of these words.
Record the word ship and remove part of the &amp;ldquo;sh&amp;rdquo; sound. Hear how it now sounds like &amp;ldquo;chip&amp;rdquo;.
Voice onset time (VOT)</description></item><item><title>Formants lab</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-11/vowel-consonant-formants-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-11/vowel-consonant-formants-lab/</guid><description>Look at this website that explains the various vowel sounds. Record several of them and compare their formants. You should see different formant shapes for each vowel sound and they should be relatively predictable.
Record the words &amp;ldquo;mood&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;mode&amp;rdquo; and compare the formants of each. Even though they are both &amp;ldquo;o&amp;rdquo; sounds, the formants will look different and their frequency ranges will differ.
Plot formants We will now make a plot out of our vowels using the first two formants.</description></item><item><title>Formatting Data for Visible Vowels</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-13/formatting-data-visible-vowels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-13/formatting-data-visible-vowels/</guid><description>Below is the final code from the tutorial. There are a few things you can change to make things a little easier and also to format the data for Visible Vowels.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 ################################################################################# # # This script extracts F1, F2, F3, and duration from all phonemes in a Sound file.</description></item><item><title>Praat Lab</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-11/praat-lab-what-can-we-see/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-11/praat-lab-what-can-we-see/</guid><description>Waveform view We will be using Praat to analyze speech data. Download and instal it from the link on the schedule page.
Record your voice speaking vowels into Praat. When you&amp;rsquo;re done recording click &amp;ldquo;View &amp;amp; Edit&amp;rdquo; to open.
Select one of the vowels to see its duration in the menu. Notice the intensity between various vowels by the hight of its waveform.
Zoom into one of the vowels by selecting it and clicking &amp;ldquo;sel&amp;rdquo; in the menu on the bottom of the window.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 Project 2 Project 3</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/24, 8/26 Tuesday 8/24:
Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? Any idea what forensic audio is? Syllabus Perusall signup I will assign readings, videos, or podcasts through Perusall.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 492 – Sound Forensics
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021
Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021
Course Meeting Time and Location: Tuesday / Thursday 1:00 pm – 2:15 pm TCB 209
Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item><item><title>Vegas Shooting Lab</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-9/vegas-shooting-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-9/vegas-shooting-lab/</guid><description>Instructions Use the analysis of the Vegas Shooting from Richard L. Mullins as a guide to recreating his analysis in spreadsheet form. He has a video where he explains a few more things if you want to watch that.
Recreate the muzzle waves timing and properties table. In Sonic Visualizer add a time value to the start of each muzzle blast. Then export the annotation layer as a CSV. Open the file in Excel, or Google Sheets, to begin your spreadsheet.</description></item></channel></rss>